m 211 -8 b 217 -6 217 -4 217 -2 l 217 24 b 217 26 217 29 211 31 l 31 31 b 26 29 26 26 26 24 l 26 -2 b 26 -4 26 -6 31 -8
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
《越狱》前情提要
Previously on Prison Break...
那些攻击越来越近了
The strikes are getting closer.
我们应该还有一天
We got a day,
■
！请人人视频停止使用人人影视字幕组译制作品。人人视频≠人人影视  望周知
顶多两天时间离开这鬼地方
maybe two, tops, to get out of this hole.
非常时期  非常手段
Desperate times, desperate measures.
m 38 -1 l 44 6 l 38 13 l 19 13 b 14 12 14 6 14 6 b 14 6 14 0 19 -1
迈克尔想联系我们
Michael's reaching out to us.
m 200 -1 l 200 13 l 19 13 b 14 12 14 6 14 6 b 14 6 14 0 19 -1
翻译     春天里的小熊  薇薇安  PiPi  徐棒棒
我们得找人帮忙  一个叫希巴的女人
We got to get help. A woman named Sheba.
你弟弟喜欢说谜语  是不是
Your brother speaks in riddles, does he?
ISIL的人  我们的车会被拦下来
ISIL. We're gonna get stopped.
翻译     普利星布里狗  高庭玫瑰  肉塔  木浅
不如我们忘记彼此的存在
Why don't we forget each other ever existed.
美人可不是那么轻易就被忘记的
Beauty's not so easily forgotten.
鸣谢       后期：小海    校对：不高兴童鞋    监制：渔夫
上头肯定有人吧  拜格威尔
Friends in high places, Bagwell.
我可以给你配备一个行动自如的义肢
I can equip you with a fully articulate prosthetic.
校对        木浅    普利星布里狗    何何    冰卡
-谁在背后指使  -没人
- Who's behind this? - ‭Nobody.
这就是卡尼尔·乌提斯
This is Kaniel Outis.
卡尼尔·乌提斯  系ISIL恐怖分子
因杀害一名中情局高级官员
并制造多起爆炸案
而被中情局  联调局通缉
好吧  但你我都知道
Okay, but you and I both know
时间轴     姜姜  大葱  壬虚浪影
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德是谁
who Michael Scofield was.
我们触发了一些事
We've awoken something,
一些被极力掩盖的关于迈克尔的事
something people are trying to hide about Michael.
雅各布
Jacob?
WEB版    时间轴     何何超人、拚命三郎、心疼自己
这就是博弈论  你会遇见别人
That's game theory. You meet people.
把他们带入自己的生活
You bring them into your life
直到
until the moment
后期      吉吉
需要为自己而利用这些关系的那一刻
you need to manipulate the relationship to your advantage.
你答应了帮他  那怎么帮
You agreed to help him... how?
只要我能想办法让全城停电
If I could arrange a blackout.
V2后期     何何超人、拚命三郎、心疼自己
他认识的一个人就能帮他逃出来
He knew someone who could get him out.
有人找到了我的父亲
Someone found my father.
总监      渔夫      何何超人、拚命三郎、心疼自己
那意味着越狱开始了
It means the escape is on.
同时  ISIL恐怖组织决心
ISIL forces are also bent on
要解救其领导人阿布·拉马尔
freeing their leader Abu Ramal,
他以其极端的观点和做法而闻名
known for his extreme views and practices.
你为我们安排好出去的路了吗
是的  就在明晚
也门  奥杰吉亚监狱
■
人人词典
使用人人词典查词学习，美剧原声朗读与例句场景
Prison Break
看  "泡泡糖侠"又给我们送东西了
他说是"泡泡糖侠"派他来的
He says Bubble Gum Man sent him.
是在监狱里的人  他也没见过
Someone in the prison he hasn't met,
不过他用泡泡糖作为给他的差遣费
but gives him gum in exchange for errands.
他说他很害怕
He says he's frightened.
告诉他没事的
Tell him it's all right.
问他收不收嘀嗒糖
Ask him if he does Tic Tacs.
如果他继续送信
He can have the whole lot
他就能拿到更多
if he keeps the messages coming.
谢谢你  "嘀嗒糖侠"
Thank you, Tic Tac Man.
嘀嗒  嘀嗒  嘀嗒
Tic Tac, Tic Tac, Tic Tacs.
这是《古兰经》中的一段文字
It's a passage from the Suras.
"然后尤瑟夫对囚犯说
"And Yusef said to the prisoner:
"在面对你们的真主时要想起我"
'Remember me in the presence of your lord.'
"但是撒旦使他忘记了这件事"
"But Satan made him forget,"
"于是尤瑟夫在监狱里被关了很多年"
"And Yusef stayed in prison for several years."
这种笔迹很古怪
The calligraphy is unusual,
空格  组成的形状
the spacing, the way it's shaped,
像是车轮上的辐条
like, like spokes on a wheel.
就像萨那的中心
Like the center of Sana'a.
你觉得他弟弟送来了一幅地图
You think his brother sent us a map?
这里有一个红点
There's a red dot
表明他所在的地方
dotting the "I",
不管这是哪里
and whatever this is here.
他想告诉我们一个位置
He's trying to give us a location.
什么的位置
A location for what?
我唯一能想到的
The only thing I can think of
就是当他今晚越狱之时
is where we're supposed to meet him
期望和我们会合的地方
when the escape goes down tonight.
现在你弟弟的事我不掺和了
Your brother is your business now.
今晚我得和家人赶在机场关闭前
I have to get my family on a flight tonight
一起上飞机
before the airport shuts down.
等等
Hold up.
我们也需要机票  我们三个人
We need tickets, too, three of them.
我  迈克尔  钞票哥
One for me, one for Michael, one for C.
如果我还能搞到机票  也会给这些孩子
If I'm getting anybody any tickets it's these kids,
不会给你唯利是图的弟弟
not your mercenary brother.
没有钱  你要怎么买到那些机票
And how are you going to do that without any money?
你要拿这些孩子的自由威胁我  是吗
You're holding these kids' freedom over my head; is that it?
希巴  只要你帮我买到那些机票
Sheba, you get me those plane tickets,
我会支付所有孩子的机票费用
and I'll pay for every single one of these kids
让他们逃出这个国家
to get out of this country.
直觉告诉我  不管怎样你都会这么做
Something tells me that's what you want to do anyhow.
说话可要小心哦
Careful.
你这是在"责备"我良心未泯
You're accusing me of having a heart.
走开  都走开
Out of my way. Get out of my way.
怎么  你想走吗
What, you want to go?
冷静点
Keep it together.
你必须万事俱备了我才能冷静
You got to have it together to keep it together.
在经历了这么长时间的炮击后
One of those hits us now,
终于有一颗炮弹击中我们这了  我发誓...
after all this time, I swear to God... ‭
九个小时
Nine hours.
我们九个小时后就能离开  你明白吗
Nine hours till we get out, you understand?
就在凌晨1点
It's 1:00 A.M.
我们熬过今天  就能逃出生天了
We get through today and we're on the bricks.
那又怎么样
And then what?
那是四年前了
It was four years ago.
我们的全部计划  护照  还有那家店
All of our plans, the passports, the shop,
现在可能全都埋在废墟下了
everything is probably under rubble by now.
我找到人来处理这件事了
I got someone on it.
什么  就那个捡你纸飞机的孩子吗
What, the kid you throw planes to?
不是
No.
我说的是这世界上我唯一信任的人
I'm talking about the only person I trust in the world
就和我信任你一样
as much as I trust you.
就是这里了  地图上的那个点
So, this is it, the spot on the map.
原主人说他四年前
The owner says he sold the auto shop
把这家汽修店卖给了一个美国人
to an American four years ago
那之后就没见过他了
and hasn't seen him since.
你知道那个美国人是迈克尔  对吧
You know that American was Michael, right?
问题是他用这个地方做什么呢
Question is what was he using this place for.
谋划他的越狱
Planning his escape.
看起来他原本的撤退点
It looks like his original exfil point
是在北面边界
was at the northern border.
现在可没法那么做了
Won't be doing that now.
那已是ISIL恐怖组织的地盘了
It's ISIL territory.
模板  护照照片
Mock-ups, passport photos,
伪装
disguises.
不过看起来他打算不只把自己弄出来
But it looks like he just wasn't planning on getting himself out.
他要把阿布·拉马尔弄出来
He was getting Abu Ramal out.
这家伙
This guy's the enemy
是一切文明发展的敌人  老林
of everything that's civilized, Linc.
这就回到我真正的问题上了
That brings me to my real question.
我们到底是在帮谁越狱
Who in the hell are we breaking out?
是迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
Is it Michael Scofield
还是卡尼尔·乌提斯
or Kaniel Outis?
越 狱 第五季第三集
把异教徒围起来
把离经叛道者也围起来
到底怎么回事
What the hell's going on?
拉马尔的人要执行伊斯兰教教法
Ramal's men are gonna institute Sharia law.
而那个混蛋却打算坐壁上观
And that son of a bitch himself is gonna enjoy the show.
我们只要低着头  熬过这关
We just have to keep our heads down and get through this
今晚就能出去了
so we can get out tonight.
把他们单独分离出来
那些玷污了我们土地的同性恋  抓住他们
他们必须为其罪行受罚
不  不  别让他们抓我走
No. No, don't let them take me!
不
No! ‭
这人是离经叛道者吗
-对不起  -不
- Sorry. - ‭No!
当一个男人
骑到另一个男人身上
真主的王权必然动摇
拉马尔
Ramal!
走开  放了他
Get back. Just let him go.
拉马尔
Ramal!
你在做什么
What are you doing?
-别管这事  -不行
- Stay out of this. - ‭No.
今晚就要越狱
The escape is tonight.
如果你想出去  你需要我  你还需要他
If you want to get out, you need me and you need him.
说重点
Get to the point.
放了他  拉马尔
Let him go, Ramal.
那我来
Then I'll do it.
别碰他
Do not touch him.
一边去  小子
Get back, dog!
这所监狱里严禁杀人  明白了吗
There will be no killing in this prison.... Understand?
他以前就试着联系过她
He's tried to contact her before.
唯一不同的是这次他成功了
Only difference is he succeeded this time.
走了那个男孩这步棋  高明
It's smart... going through the boy.
问一个问题
Ask a question?
我们为什么不跟这个女人来硬的了
Why are we pulling our punches with this woman?
几天前姐被派去她家
I got sent to her house a couple of days ago,
才准备大开杀戒  却在姐杀她之前
started spilling blood, but I'm just supposed to stop
给姐喊停了
before I start spilling hers.
这是怎么回事
How's that work?
你会习惯波塞冬的游戏规则的
You'll get used to Poseidon's game.
这就是一盘棋
It's all chess.
就是一场秀
It's a performance.
一场设计好  让乌提斯联系她的表演
A performance designed to make Outis reach out to her.
现在我们要做的就是窃听
Now all we got to do is listen in,
弄清楚他的葫芦里到底卖的什么药
find out what his plans are.
而且她还没有察觉
And she doesn't know it.
她就是能帮我们顺藤摸瓜的人
She's the one that's going to lead us to him.
他们说我上午可以出院了
They said I can go in the morning.
你的股动脉被切断了
Your femoral artery was severed.
这可不是通常那种站起来就能没事走人的伤
That's not something you usually just get up and walk away from.
他们跟我说可以了
Hey, they gave me the okay.
他们才是主治医生  而不是你
They're the doctors on this one, not you.
而且我现在已经恢复清醒了  所以我要出院
And I'm going full mental in here, so I'm gonna go.
好吧  这样如何
Okay. How about this?
等你真能出院时
When you are discharged,
我们去你父母的湖畔小屋怎么样
why don't we go up to your parents' lake house?
我和麦克一起接上你就出发
I'll just pick you up with Mike and we'll go.
你不想在家里待着  对不对
You don't want to be in the house, do you?
有人闯进你家
Somebody comes into your house
朝你丈夫开枪  而且仍然逍遥法外
and shoots up your husband and they're still out there.
不想
No.
怎么了
‭What?
没什么  就是你下定决心的时候
No, it's just something you do with your nose
会动鼻子
when you're determined.
-动鼻子  -很难察觉
- With my nose? - ‭It's subtle.
-真的很难察觉  -最好是
- I mean, it's really subtle. - Better be.
你的脸真精致
The face is amazing.
我是说
I mean,
最细微的细节  哪怕失之毫厘
the tiniest detail, less than a millimeter,
也会差之千里
differentiates everything.
同一种表情在一个人的脸上可以是
An emotion on one person can be...
非常心神不安的
so troubled
而在另一个人脸上
and on another...
却如此美丽动人
...so beautiful.
你不是在动什么坏主意吧  奈斯先生
You're not trying to get somewhere, are you, Mr. Ness?
事实上
Yes, actually,
还真是
I am.
手机已锁
手机已解锁
你好啊
Hello there.
我们是一伙的  莎拉
I come as a compatriot, Sara.
你给我闪开  不然我就喊了
Get out of my way or I'll scream.
我也不希望那样
Last thing I want.
不妨先听听我说的
For your information,
我知道卡尼尔·乌提斯的事
I know about Kaniel Outis.
说说你都知道什么
Tell me what you know.
我从福克斯河监狱刑满释放那天
The day I hit the bricks from Fox River,
有个叫乌提斯的人
someone named Outis,
大发善心
out of the goodness of their soul,
主动捐给我这个现代义肢
unsolicited, pays for this modern prosthesis.
你说什么
What's that?
一百万美元
A million bucks?
为什么会有人对我这样的卑鄙小人倾囊相助呢
Why would anyone come out of a pocket for a wretch like me,
一分都不可能  更别说一百万了
a penny, much less a million bucks?
如果你是来找我要答案的话  我也不知道
Yeah, if you're coming to me for answers, I don't have any.
我找过答案了  莎拉医生
Oh, I went looking for answers, Doc Sara.
我在网上查询了乌提斯这个人
I looked up Outis on the Interwebs.
结果出现了你已故前夫的脸
Whose face comes up but your dead ex-husband's,
看着生龙活虎着呢
looking very much alive.
拉撒路死而复生
Lazarus arisen from the dead.
[拉撒路  在圣经约翰福音中因病而死
最后被耶稣复活]
他是不是想找我们做什么事
He's drawing us into something, isn't he?
他是不是想要什么东西
He wants something, doesn't he?
你要是再接近我或者我的家人  我就杀了你
Come near me or my family again, I will kill you.
你最好是和我站在同一战线上  莎拉
Better to have me on your side, Sara.
我们可以一起解决的
We can figure this out together.
我们都听说了外面的战争
We have all heard the war outside.
但是就算战争只在高墙之内
But even if it is just within these walls,
这个国家的法律仍然健在
the law of the land is still in place.
真主之法凌驾于这腐朽之国的法律之上
The law of God supersedes the law of this corrupt land.
我们不会再退化回动物
We will not be reduced to animals.
你还信任他真是不可思议
Amazing you still trust him.
他会利用你越狱然后就甩了你
He will use you for the escape and he will leave you.
没有人要越狱
No one's escaping.
你是什么人
Who are you?
这个监狱里最了解
A man who knows your friend there
你朋友的人
more than anyone in this prison.
我跟他一起关禁闭好多年
I was in solitary with him for years.
我也是
Yeah, so was I.
但你没关在他对面的禁闭室里过
But not in the cell across from him.
他跟我说过越狱的事情
He told me about the escape.
-我们必须联手  -不行
- We have to work together. - ‭No.
他曾试图说服我跟他一起越狱
Tried to convince me to go with him,
只有我们两个人
just the two of us.
但是我拒绝了他
But I told him no.
我是不会离开我兄弟的
I would not leave my brother.
我内心仍有军纪
That is the Army in me,
我内心仍是基督徒
the Christian in me.
他是个机会主义者
He is an opportunist.
他会利用任何他所需要的人
He will use whoever he needs.
他已经跟你说过越狱的事情了  我知道
He has told you something about the escape. I know he has.
你跟他在一个牢房里  你
You were in the cell with him. You.
你告诉我  我就能帮你
You tell me, so I can help you,
赶在他利用你把那个大魔头弄出监狱
before he uses you to get that devil out
把我们留在这里等死之前
and we are all left here to die.
我们需要护照  奥玛  你能帮我们吗
We need passports, Omar. You think you can help us?
等等  我们能信得过这家伙吗
Hold on. We're gonna trust this guy?
他可是偷我护照在先的人
He's the one who stole my passport in the first place.
那可是诚信交易  朋友
It was honest bargaining, friend.
我什么都没得到
I took nothing.
再说  你的护照早没了
Besides, your passport is long gone,
我估计现在已经远在天边了
somewhere far overseas by now, I bet.
如果你想  我可以让办假证的再给你弄个
If you want, um, I can have the forgers make you another.
让你制作我自己的假护照吗
My own fake passport coming from you?
你有别的选择吗
You have another option?
快  我要离开这里
Quick. I'm leaving the city.
这里已经没有地方是安全的了
Nowhere is safe anymore.
我需要两个护照  一个给我的
I need two passports. One for me,
一个给我弟弟的  迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
one for my brother, Michael Scofield.
每个护照预付一千美元
$1,000 U.S. each, deposit.
取货的时候每个再付一千美元
$1,000 U.S. when you pick them up.
钞票哥
C?
如果你敢耍我  我就杀了你
You screw with me and I'll kill you.
如果我耍你  我才不会让你找到我
I screw you, I won't be around for you to kill me.
今晚十一点  希巴
11 tonight, Sheba.
护照会准备好的
Passports will be ready.
那我们就得分头行动了
That means we're gonna have to split up.
你们俩去拿护照
You two get the passports,
我和这位朋友一起去发电厂
and I'll go with our friend here to the power plant
搞定停电熄灯的活儿
and kill the lights.
然后我们救迈克尔出来
And we get Michael out.
美国国务院的一位发言人称
A U.S. State Department spokesperson said
也门首都日趋沦陷
the capital of Yemen grows ever closer to collapse
萨那落入ISIL激进分子手中
and it's only a matter of time
只是时间问题罢了
until Sana'a's fallen to the hands of ISIL radicals,
预计最快明天就会彻底沦陷
with the total collapse coming as soon as tomorrow.
要买智能手机吗
Looking for a smartphone?
对  你...
Yeah. You, um...
你也能修手机  对吗
you fix phones, too, right?
对
Yeah.
我觉得有人黑了我的手机
I think somebody hacked my cell.
有可能帮我找出是谁干的吗
Is there any chance you can help me figure out who?
这院子里并不安全
只给十分钟吃饭时间
如果想吃饭  现在赶紧
我才不要为了让你们填饱肚子而死在这里
那个基督徒说  你告诉了他你会带上他
That Christian guy said you told him you'd just take him.
不带其他人
No one else.
他是骗子  你最好别跟他扯上任何关系
He's a liar. You don't want anything to do with him.
我可说不准  基督徒  军人
I don't know. Christian, Army.
-我觉得挺可信  -那他有没有告诉你
- Seems pretty upfront to me. -Did he happen to tell you
他和他兄弟在他们的安检哨卡
about some of the arrests he and his brother made
-抓的那些人呢  -没  只顾着说你了
- at their security checkpoint?  - No, focused on you.
他们专抓一种人  女人
They had a specialty: women.
尸段遍布也门
Body parts strewn around Yemen.
这就是他们被关进来的原因
That's why they're here.
戴着十字架是一回事
Wearing a cross is one thing.
-以此为生就是另一回事了  -好  行了
- Living by it is another. - All right, okay, sure.
只要保证我们今晚仍会行动
Just promise me I can trust you,
而且我能信任你就行
that we're still doing this tonight.
我们一起合作这么多年
All these years we've been working together,
你一直都能信任我
you've been able to trust me the whole time.
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
最新海外影视剧下载
过去四年都在洞里  在黑暗中生活
Last four years in the hole, sitting in the dark,
我甚至连什么声音都听不到  我可说不准
I couldn't even hear a voice. I don't know.
说不定有什么变数或者
Maybe something's changed or...
没有变数
Nothing's changed.
波塞冬把我们安排到这里去救拉马尔
Poseidon put us in here to get Ramal out,
但他又抛弃了我们
but then he abandoned us.
拉马尔是波塞冬的人  不是我们的
Ramal is Poseidon's guy, not ours.
-他是个禽兽  -你最好小心说话
- He's an animal. - I suggest you watch your mouth.
他们有人懂英语
Some of these guys speak English.
我们为什么还要把他弄出去
Why are we still getting him out?
我们只是跟他说要救他出去
We're telling him we're getting him out.
两者是有区别的
There's a difference.
我们必须表现出我们是跟他一伙的
We got to act like we're on his side
直到我们不需要他为止
until the moment we're not.
但万一你也是表现出是跟我一伙的
But what if you're acting like you're on my side
直到你不需要我为止呢
till the moment you're not?
你太多心了
You are getting paranoid.
换做把你关四年禁闭  你也会这样的
Yeah, well, four years in the box is gonna do that to you.
我不会抛下你的
I'm not leaving you behind.
-你是我的得力干将  -我不确认这点
- You're my whip hand. - I don't know that.
我怎么确信我是你的得力干将呢
How do I know I'm your whip hand?
-之后你会明白的  -我现在就要明白
- You'll understand later. - I want to understand now.
好吗
Okay?
把你的手放开
Get your hands off me.
现在给我答案  我是很认真的
Answers, now. I'm serious.
好吧
Okay.
我说了别碰我
I said don't touch me!
好吧
Okay.
好吧  这才像话
Okay, that's fair.
你还想被关到洞里去吗
You want the hole again, huh?
不  我们没事
No, we're good.
不
No.
我们没事
We're good.
我们没事才怪
We're far from good.
等到明天  我们就不用再担心他了
By tomorrow, we won't have to worry about him.
萨那  伪造者之区
把头低下
Keep your head down.
不要和任何人对视
Don't make eye contact with anybody.
到处都有ISIL恐怖组织的支持者
A lot of ISIL sympathizers everywhere.
我们拿了护照就离开
We get our passports, we're out of here.
明白吗
Understand?
打算离开吗
Planning on leaving?
正当光荣革命即将开始之际
Right when the glorious revolution is beginning.
我不是来讨论政治的  只是拿护照
I'm not here for political discussion, just passports.
先交钱
Money first.
先看护照
Passports first.
护照是空白的
They're empty.
希巴
Sheba! ‭
抱歉我打了你  我可以解释
I'm sorry I hit you. I can explain.
你能解释得了为什么
Can you explain why
你打算让那人杀了我吗
you were going to let that man kill me?
我不会让他杀了你的
I wouldn't have let him kill you.
看来你和ISIL恐怖组织老大确实是好基友
You sure seem to be chums with the head of ISIL, friend.
没想到你也会加入我们的谈话了  雅
Didn't know you participated in these conversations, Ja.
我只谈论有意思的话题
Only when they're interesting.
不过通常都没意思
And they're usually not.
随你信不信
There are people in my government,
我政府里有人因为
believe it or not, who want that man out
他们自己复杂的外交政策而要那人出狱
for their own convoluted foreign policy over here.
这是维普和我被派来做的事
That's the job Whip and I were sent here to do.
但是因为某些原因  我们被抛弃了
But for some reason, we were betrayed.
也就是说这次越狱没有拉马尔的份了
Which means we're getting out without Ramal.
你们每个人都是计划中重要的一环
And every one of you is crucial to that plan.
怎么讲
How?
你的整个越狱计划早已酝酿成形
Your whole escape's already wired.
灯一熄  你就越过高墙
Lights out, you're over the wall.
你还要我这样的韩国瘾君子做什么
What do you need a Korean junkie like me for?
你的意思其实是韩国天才
Korean genius, you mean.
翻越那堵高墙只是开始
Getting over that wall is just the start.
一旦完成
Once that happens,
就有些只有你能做到的事
there are things only you can do.
回到重点上来  你打了我
Back on point: you hit me.
你要我证明我和你一伙儿  而不是拉马尔
You wanted proof that I sided with you and not Ramal.
打烂我的嘴唇算什么证据
And splitting my lip does that how?
狗娘养的卡尼尔·乌提斯就是爱演  对不对
Son of a bitch Kaniel Outis keeps playing, doesn't he?
我的手表在哪
Where is my watch?
我不知道你在说些什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你不知道吗
You don't?
等我找到表了
I'm going to break you in half
我要把你劈成两半
when I find that watch, you know?
把这间牢房翻个底朝天
Toss the cell.
表不在这
It's not here.
下令整个监狱实行一级防范性禁闭
Order a lockdown of the whole prison.
不允许任何人走出牢房一步
No one gets out of their cells
直到找到那块表为止
until that watch is found!
回你牢房里去
一级防范性禁闭
进去
我说过  拉马尔哪也去不了
I told you, Ramal's not going anywhere.
只有我们能逃出去
Only we are.
我们会跟其他人一样被锁在自己的囚室里
We're gonna be locked in our box just like the rest of them,
然而只有我们的囚室能逃出去
only our box has a way out.
等两个小时以后  那些灯都灭了
And in two hours when those lights go black,
我们会像幽灵一样从这里消失不见
we're gonna disappear from this place like ghosts.
随便吧
Yeah, all right.
希巴
Sheba!
跟你一伙的都是些什么人
Who are these men you work with?
他们配不上你
They're beneath you.
你才配不上我
You're beneath me.
伤害你我也心痛
It pains me to hurt you,
但良家妇女就得恪守妇道
but a good woman is a humble woman.
给我记住了
Remember that.
那些人是谁
Who are these men?
不重要
Doesn't matter.
反正他们要离开了
They're leaving.
坏人不是我
I am not the bad guy here.
你我有过一段情
You and I have a history.
上小学时我曾是何等地宠爱你的
How I doted on you in grade school,
我又曾是如何等了又等
how I waited and I waited.
你没有等
You did not wait.
你只想强奸我
You tried to rape me!
求你了
Please.
行行好  松开我
Please. Please untie me...
这样我就可以让你再瞎一只眼
...so I can take your other eye.
下午好
Afternoon.
我在找我那一部被一个女人偷走的手机
I'm looking for a cell phone that a woman stole from me.
她长这样  对吧
She looks like this?
不  我帮不了你
No, can't help you.
帮不了  还是不愿帮
Can't... or won't?
不好意思  只不过店里有规矩
Sorry. Store policy, that's all.
关门
你们要做什么
What are you doing?
我再问一次
‭Let's go again.
你见过她没有
Have you seen her? ‭
见过  见过
Yes. Yes!
她刚来过  大概十分钟前吧
She was here, like, ten minutes ago.
说她手机被黑了  想知道是谁干的
Said her phone was hacked and wanted to know who did it.
她现在知道了  不是吗
And now she knows, doesn't she?
她给我们下套
She baited us.
是死胡同
Dead end.
波塞冬有没有可能让我们直接杀了她
Any chance Poseidon'll just let us kill her?
将来也许会吧
It might come to that.
我们出去了  你会去哪里
We get out, where are you going?
回我沙发上
Back to my couch.
我首尔的沙发上
My couch in Seoul,
那里的墙是我的
where the walls are mine,
地板是我的
the floors are mine.
没人能管我
No one can get to me.
墙外面的世界有它该有的样子
The world stays outside like it's supposed to.
卡尔加里
Calgary.
加拿大吗
Canada?
我要去当跳台滑雪运动员
I'm going to be a ski jumper.
你从没见过雪  对吧
You've never seen snow, have you?
所以才选那里
That's the point.
我到目前在这个国家所经历的一切
Everything in my life till now in this country--
炎热  仇恨  从不下雪的天
the heat, the hate, the skies that never snow.
你所谈论的那种"墙里世界"
You talk about the world.
我想待在那堵"墙"外面[过另一种生活]
I want to be on the other side of it.
纽约州北部
-爸爸  妈妈  -儿子
- Hey, Dad. Hey, Mom. - Hi, son.
-莎拉  让我来  -谢谢你
- Now, Sara, let me, uh... ‭- Thanks, sir.
-房子看起来真不错  -快请进
- The house looks great. - Come on in.
稍等一下  不好意思
Oh, give me one sec. Sorry.
喂
Hello?
你好  我是捷普数码店的布莱恩
Hi. This is Brian at Jep's.
我给你激活新手机时记下了你的号码
I got this number when I activated your new phone.
你一直没回来
You never came back.
很抱歉  我想我不会回去了
I'm sorry. I don't think I'm going to.
好吧  我只想告诉你我发现了
Well, okay, I just want to let you know that
是谁在黑你的手机
I figured out who was hacking your phone.
是谁
Who?
是你...  黑了你自己的手机
You... hacked your own phone.
你在说些什么
What are you talking about?
你的拇指指纹就是秘钥  对吧
Your thumbprint is your password, right?
那个黑你手机的人用了你的指纹
Well, whoever hacked your phone used your thumbprint,
所以说  除非你大拇指丢了
so, unless you're missing a thumb,
否则就是你自己
that's you.
我不知道你惹了什么麻烦
I don't know what you're messed up in,
但换做是我  我一定会多加小心了
but I'd watch your back...
你在医院的时候
When you were in the hospital,
袭击我们的女人跟她的同伙又回来了
the woman who attacked us came back with her partner.
什么
What?
他们利用我的手机跟踪了我
They tracked me down using my cell phone,
所以我把手机拿去捷普数码店
so I brought it to Jep's
想找出他们的幕后老板是谁
to try and figure out who they were working for.
等等  莎拉  这事有警方全权负责
Wait. Sara, this has police written all over it.
警方没有解决问题的能力
Police haven't been able to do a thing.
所以呢  你就去了捷普数码店
So, what? You went to Jep's Electronics
试图用反侦察的滥招数搞定吗
in some hackneyed attempt at counter-espionage?
抱歉  抱歉  我只是...
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. It's just...
我明白你有点不知所措
I get you don't know where to turn,
但这也是我的事
but I got a stake in this, too.
好吧  这可事关我的老婆和儿子
‭Okay? This is my wife, my son.
你想报复这帮家伙吗
You want to get back at these guys?
那就去大学
The university.
我是说  那里有资源
I mean, it has real resources,
有计算机科学系
their Computer Sciences Department.
手机的事到此为止  我会把它留在捷普
The phone's done. It's gonna stay at Jep's.
所以你的计划就是  逃避现实吗
So that's your plan-- just bury your head in the sand?
不
No.
不  我这些年学到了
No, I've learned over the years
逃避是最坏的选择  谢谢你了
that's exactly what you don't do. Thank you.
你是哪位
Which one's this?
你在卫生间里搭讪的那位
The one you accosted in a bathroom.
那可不是搭讪  亲爱的
That wasn't accostment, honey.
我搞清楚了一些有关于
I've learned some things
我们两个都在找的那个人的事
about who it is we're apparently both looking for?
但我需要知道你有决心坚持到底
But I need to know that you're willing to go the distance.
我最有决心了  小美人儿
I'm made of the distance, honeysuckle.
我就是决心的化身
I am the distance.
很好  因为你需要替我去
Good. Because you're gonna have a conversation
和保罗·凯勒曼聊聊
with Paul Kellerman for me.
不会吧  凯勒曼是幕后主使吗
Bull. Kellerman's behind this?
你得去查清楚这到底是怎么回事
And you are gonna get every shred of information you can
不要放过一丝一毫的线索
about what's really going on.
十五分钟
15 minutes.
我只是想告诉你  这次是我自己打脸了
I'm soiling myself here, just so you know.
听着  我只说这一件事  好吗
Look, I'm just gonna say one thing, okay?
你就像我的兄弟
You're like a brother to me,
就像一位老大哥一样
like an older brother.
-我不是个好大哥  -确实
- I'm not much of a brother. - ‭Sure.
但重点是之前我一个兄弟都没
Point is that I had zero, nobody,
直到你拉我入伙
till you recruited me.
把我从奥沙克监狱救出来的你
When you pulled me out of that prison in the Ozarks,
作风正派
you had integrity.
当然  当时我知道那是中情局的差事
I know we were doing CIA work, sure,
救他们要的人出去啊什么的
you know, pulling their people out,
但重要的是我们并肩作战
but it was about you and me,
我们把性命都托付给对方
and having each other's back.
之前从哥伦比亚越狱那次也一样
And it didn't matter if you were Ramon Cadena
就算你化名罗曼·卡德纳  我也不在乎
when we did the Colombian break,
还有  阿萨夫...
or, you know Asaf...
他叫什么来着
What was his name?
随便吧  就是埃及那次
Whatever. The one in Egypt.
你还是那个你
You were still you.
这次也一样
And it's the same with this one.
我们让你化名为卡尼尔·乌提斯
You know, we trump you up as Kaniel Outis,
伪装成国际恐怖分子
big international terrorist.
那只是个名字
It's just a name,
只是张罪行累累的"狼皮"  一个进监狱的借口
it's just a rap sheet, it's a way to get you locked up.
对吧
Right?
我大概想问你的是...
I guess what I'm asking you is did...
你单独监禁时是不是发生了什么事
did something happen to you while you were in solitary?
你是不是真相信自己是卡尼尔·乌提斯了
Did you become Kaniel Outis in there in your head?
你是不是真想把拉马尔救出去了
Do you now want Ramal out after all?
我告诉过你了  我们不管拉马尔了
I already told you Ramal is out of the picture.
你是说了  但有件小事...
Yeah, you said that, but one small thing...
计划是我们从上面那个洞口出去
We go up through that hole,
从囚区上面绕着走
and then we skirt above the block.
走到拉马尔囚室正上方  不是吗
Goes right above Ramal's cell, doesn't it?
敲掉几块砖
Knock out a couple tiles,
他就跟我们一起跑了  对吧
he joins the escape, doesn't he?
刚才我们吵完架后
What did you whisper to him
你跟他悄悄说了什么
in that moment after the fight?
你跟他说悄悄话了  说了什么
You whispered something, what was it?
九分钟
Nine minutes.
你怎么知道的
How do you know?
刚吃晚饭时  他跟我说的
He told me at dinner.
他说他会来救我们
He said he would come for us.
本来只接我一个
It's supposed to be only me,
但我会带上你们
but you will all be coming.
打开五号囚区的门
Open block five.
所有人都出来
Everyone out.
给我彻底搜查
Shakedown.
找到了
Got it.
找到了  穆斯塔法
Found it, Mustapha.
在埃米尔的大衣里
It was in the Emir's coat here.
你相信了那个骗子的鬼话  是吗
You trusted the liar, didn't you?
现在我们只要祈祷灯如约熄灭
Now, we just pray they get the lights out.
萨那  电气工程部
我们得快点了  伙计
We got to hurry, man.
不到十分钟就得断电了
We got less than ten minutes to kill the power.
别担心
Don't worry.
幸运的话  你朋友和我儿子
With luck, both your friend and my son
一小时内就会重获自由了
will be free within the hour.
好的  断路器已关闭
Okay, breakers are down.
现在只要断掉备用电源就行
Now, we just need to pull the redundancies.
就在大厅那头
They're down the hall.
我留下对付保安  快去
I'll stay here and deal with security. Go.
好
Okay.
拜托  你在哪啊
Come on, where are you?
不是吧
Come on.
犹豫不决时  就用老办法
When in doubt, go old school.
我们走
Let's go.
启动发电机
Get the generators up.
让囚犯都进去
Get these inmates back inside!
快
Now! ‭
我们走  我们走
Let's go, let's go!
武器  把他们的武器抢过来
The weapons, get their weapons.
他们想丢下我们自己跑路
They are trying to escape without us.
快去他们的牢房
Get to their cell.
六号囚区  快走
Block six. Come on!
你听到了  兄弟
You heard them, brother.
-六号囚区  -好
- Block six. - ‭Yes.
雅  把你电话给我
Ja, give me your phone.
快
Come on.
配上强光手电
Mount flashlights.
检查每间囚室
Secure every room.
不到万不得已  不要开枪
Shoot only if you have to.
逼不得已时  格杀勿论
And if you do, shoot to kill.
这边
This way.
去六号囚区的近路  兄弟  快
A shortcut to block six, brother, come on!
放开我  你个畜生
Get off me, you sick bastard!
你不挣扎就能少受点罪
It's easier if you don't struggle.
你就这样对我吗
‭This is how you treat me?
准备受死吧  疯狗
You're going to die now, dog.
希巴  希巴  是我  是我
Sheba, Sheba, it's me, it's me.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
林肯  怎么样
Linc, talk to me.
去接头点  汽修店
Get to the rendezvous, the auto shop.
我们赶不到了
We ain't gonna make it.
希巴伤得很重
Sheba's busted up real bad.
-怎么回事  -快去接头点
- What happened? - Just get to the rendezvous.
我们必须要去接迈克尔  该死的
We got to be there for Michael, damn it!
该死  一级防范性禁闭了
Damn. Lockdown.
屋顶上有更多卫兵
Extra guards on the roof.
问题在于他们动不动
Question is whether they move on.
快点  快  快
Quickly! Hurry, hurry!
在这里  这间
It's here, this one!
有麻烦了
We got problems.
-有人要进我们牢房  -有麻烦了
- Guys are trying to get into the cell. - Problem.
-怎么了  -有人来了
- What's wrong? - People coming.
该死的  上面有卫兵
Damn it, we got guards up here.
争取点时间
Try and buy us some time.
交给我
I'm taking care of it.
不好  他们要逃跑了  快
No, they're escaping, hurry!
不  求求你  别丢下我们
No, please! Don't leave us.
求你了  我们是基督徒
Please, we are Christians,
他们会杀了我们的  求你了
they will kill us! Please!
不行  上面还不安全
No, we're still not clear up top.
别让他们上来
Make sure they don't get up.
走
Go!
他们来了  雅
They're coming, Ja.
-怎么样  -不太妙
- How we doing? - Not good.
卫兵靠得更近了
Guards are even closer.
你快上去
Pull yourself up!
帮帮忙  帮帮忙
Help, help!
希德
Sid!
帮帮我
Help me out!
先把他拉上来
Get him up here first.
没门儿
That's not how this works.
你们先把我弟弟拉上去
You pull my brother up first.
快点  拉马尔来了
Hurry, Ramal is coming.
搭把手  我发誓我要...
Lend me your hand. I swear I'm gonna...
先把那孩子拉上来
The kid comes up first!
退后  退后
Step away, step away.
不  穆萨  穆萨  看着我
No! Muza, Muza, look at me!
穆萨  穆萨
Muza! Muza!
不  看着我  兄弟
No! No, look at me, brother.
快快快  拉马尔来了
Go, go, go! It's Ramal.
看着我  穆萨
Look at me! Muza!
快点  我们必须一分钟之内出去
Hurry. We've got a minute tops to get out of here.
上去  去追他
Get up there, after him.
放下枪
Drop them!
把枪放下
Put it down!
快点
Do it!
不
No!
放下  快
Down, now!
木板横在缺口处  毯子盖住铁丝网
Board spans the gap. Blanket covers the wire.
出去
Get out!
你在这间牢房里干什么
What are you doing in this cell?
他们在房顶上
They're on the roof!
别开枪
Don't shoot!
我信任过你  卡尼尔·乌提斯
I trusted you, Kaniel Outis.
你却骗了我
And you lied to me.
我以真主和"哈里发"王国军队的名义
By God and my armies of the caliphate,
要你以死谢罪
you will die for it.
或许就在明天
Maybe even tomorrow.
莎拉
Sara...
我说这些话会让你身陷险境
I'm putting you in danger by saying this,
但可能也没关系  因为我到时已死
but maybe it doesn't matter because I'll be dead,
那么他们就会放过你
and they'll leave you alone.
但我爱你
But I love you.
真的  我爱着你
You see, I loved you.
我从未停止过爱你
I never stopped loving you.
这整个骗局  都是为了你
This whole lie, it was for you.
■
微信扫瞄
上方二维码
关注TV哔
一起哔哔哔
m 350 100 l 350 110 l 360 110 l 360 100 m 360 100 m 100 320 l 100 330 l 110 330 l 110 320 m 110 320 m 260 230 l 260 240 l 270 240 l 270 230 m 270 230 m 220 230 l 220 240 l 230 240 l 230 230 m 230 230 m 270 300 l 270 310 l 280 310 l 280 300 m 280 300 m 360 60 l 360 70 l 370 70 l 370 60 m 370 60 m 130 40 l 130 50 l 140 50 l 140 40 m 140 40 m 180 350 l 180 360 l 190 360 l 190 350 m 190 350 m 190 340 l 190 350 l 200 350 l 200 340 m 200 340 m 150 260 l 150 270 l 160 270 l 160 260 m 160 260 m 40 210 l 40 220 l 50 220 l 50 210 m 50 210 m 180 50 l 180 60 l 190 60 l 190 50 m 190 50 m 160 210 l 160 220 l 170 220 l 170 210 m 170 210 m 290 190 l 290 200 l 300 200 l 300 190 m 300 190 m 170 240 l 170 250 l 180 250 l 180 240 m 180 240 m 300 160 l 300 170 l 310 170 l 310 160 m 310 160 m 330 210 l 330 220 l 340 220 l 340 210 m 340 210 m 70 60 l 70 70 l 80 70 l 80 60 m 80 60 m 340 180 l 340 190 l 350 190 l 350 180 m 350 180 m 320 140 l 320 150 l 330 150 l 330 140 m 330 140 m 90 280 l 90 290 l 100 290 l 100 280 m 100 280 m 330 150 l 330 160 l 340 160 l 340 150 m 340 150 m 240 180 l 240 190 l 250 190 l 250 180 m 250 180 m 220 140 l 220 150 l 230 150 l 230 140 m 230 140 m 270 230 l 270 240 l 280 240 l 280 230 m 280 230 m 250 190 l 250 200 l 260 200 l 260 190 m 260 190 m 260 160 l 260 170 l 270 170 l 270 160 m 270 160 m 130 130 l 130 140 l 140 140 l 140 130 m 140 130 m 270 130 l 270 140 l 280 140 l 280 130 m 280 130 m 140 180 l 140 190 l 150 190 l 150 180 m 150 180 m 150 190 l 150 200 l 160 200 l 160 190 m 160 190 m 130 230 l 130 240 l 140 240 l 140 230 m 140 230 m 280 250 l 280 260 l 290 260 l 290 250 m 290 250 m 160 120 l 160 130 l 170 130 l 170 120 m 170 120 m 290 200 l 290 210 l 300 210 l 300 200 m 300 200 m 310 100 l 310 110 l 320 110 l 320 100 m 320 100 m 60 160 l 60 170 l 70 170 l 70 160 m 70 160 m 330 80 l 330 90 l 340 90 l 340 80 m 340 80 m 70 210 l 70 220 l 80 220 l 80 210 m 80 210 m 200 110 l 200 120 l 210 120 l 210 110 m 210 110 m 100 180 l 100 190 l 110 190 l 110 180 m 110 180 m 340 310 l 340 320 l 350 320 l 350 310 m 350 310 m 110 190 l 110 200 l 120 200 l 120 190 m 120 190 m 240 250 l 240 260 l 250 260 l 250 250 m 250 250 m 200 330 l 200 340 l 210 340 l 210 330 m 210 330 m 100 360 l 100 370 l 110 370 l 110 360 m 110 360 m 250 120 l 250 130 l 260 130 l 260 120 m 260 120 m 210 280 l 210 290 l 220 290 l 220 280 m 220 280 m 140 130 l 140 140 l 150 140 l 150 130 m 150 130 m 120 290 l 120 300 l 130 300 l 130 290 m 130 290 m 150 80 l 150 90 l 160 90 l 160 80 m 160 80 m 130 240 l 130 250 l 140 250 l 140 240 m 140 240 m 280 320 l 280 330 l 290 330 l 290 320 m 290 320 m 190 140 l 190 150 l 200 150 l 200 140 m 200 140 m 150 300 l 150 310 l 160 310 l 160 300 m 160 300 m 300 340 l 300 350 l 310 350 l 310 340 m 310 340 m 40 90 l 40 100 l 50 100 l 50 90 m 50 90 m 280 60 l 280 70 l 290 70 l 290 60 m 290 60 m 160 330 l 160 340 l 170 340 l 170 330 m 170 330 m 50 40 l 50 50 l 60 50 l 60 40 m 60 40 m 80 150 l 80 160 l 90 160 l 90 150 m 90 150 m 320 280 l 320 290 l 330 290 l 330 280 m 330 280 m 90 140 l 90 150 l 100 150 l 100 140 m 100 140 m 330 330 l 330 340 l 340 340 l 340 330 m 340 330 m 100 50 l 100 60 l 110 60 l 110 50 m 110 50 m 340 60 l 340 70 l 350 70 l 350 60 m 350 60 m 80 210 l 80 220 l 90 220 l 90 210 m 90 210 m 230 310 l 230 320 l 240 320 l 240 310 m 240 310 m 350 310 l 350 320 l 360 320 l 360 310 m 360 310 m 200 240 l 200 250 l 210 250 l 210 240 m 210 240 m 100 310 l 100 320 l 110 320 l 110 310 m 110 310 m 360 270 l 360 280 l 370 280 l 370 270 m 370 270 m 260 340 l 260 350 l 270 350 l 270 340 m 270 340 m 220 260 l 220 270 l 230 270 l 230 260 m 230 260 m 120 40 l 120 50 l 130 50 l 130 40 m 130 40 m 140 300 l 140 310 l 150 310 l 150 300 m 150 300 m 40 320 l 40 330 l 50 330 l 50 320 m 50 320 m 160 240 l 160 250 l 170 250 l 170 240 m 170 240 m 310 240 l 310 250 l 320 250 l 320 240 m 320 240 m 170 290 l 170 300 l 180 300 l 180 290 m 180 290 m 60 340 l 60 350 l 70 350 l 70 340 m 70 340 m 300 70 l 300 80 l 310 80 l 310 70 m 310 70 m 310 140 l 310 150 l 320 150 l 320 140 m 320 140 m 80 280 l 80 290 l 90 290 l 90 280 m 90 280 m 230 360 l 230 370 l 240 370 l 240 360 m 240 360 m 350 40 l 350 50 l 360 50 l 360 40 m 360 40 m 200 150 l 200 160 l 210 160 l 210 150 m 210 150 m 100 220 l 100 230 l 110 230 l 110 220 m 110 220 m 250 300 l 250 310 l 260 310 l 260 300 m 260 300 m 270 240 l 270 250 l 280 250 l 280 240 m 280 240 m 250 80 l 250 90 l 260 90 l 260 80 m 260 80 m 120 110 l 120 120 l 130 120 l 130 110 m 130 110 m 360 80 l 360 90 l 370 90 l 370 80 m 370 80 m 260 150 l 260 160 l 270 160 l 270 150 m 270 150 m 180 110 l 180 120 l 190 120 l 190 110 m 190 110 m 50 220 l 50 230 l 60 230 l 60 220 m 60 220 m 290 170 l 290 180 l 300 180 l 300 170 m 300 170 m 170 220 l 170 230 l 180 230 l 180 220 m 180 220 m 70 80 l 70 90 l 80 90 l 80 80 m 80 80 m 320 80 l 320 90 l 330 90 l 330 80 m 330 80 m 350 130 l 350 140 l 360 140 l 360 130 m 360 130 m 90 100 l 90 110 l 100 110 l 100 100 m 100 100 m 330 130 l 330 140 l 340 140 l 340 130 m 340 130 m 200 60 l 200 70 l 210 70 l 210 60 m 210 60 m 340 260 l 340 270 l 350 270 l 350 260 m 350 260 m 350 270 l 350 280 l 360 280 l 360 270 m 360 270 m 90 360 l 90 370 l 100 370 l 100 360 m 100 360 m 120 180 l 120 190 l 130 190 l 130 180 m 130 180 m 260 60 l 260 70 l 270 70 l 270 60 m 270 60 m 140 160 l 140 170 l 150 170 l 150 160 m 150 160 m 120 240 l 120 250 l 130 250 l 130 240 m 130 240 m 150 50 l 150 60 l 160 60 l 160 50 m 160 50 m 130 210 l 130 220 l 140 220 l 140 210 m 140 210 m 280 270 l 280 280 l 290 280 l 290 270 m 290 270 m 180 180 l 180 190 l 190 190 l 190 180 m 190 180 m 290 260 l 290 270 l 300 270 l 300 260 m 300 260 m 190 190 l 190 200 l 200 200 l 200 190 m 200 190 m 40 40 l 40 50 l 50 50 l 50 40 m 50 40 m 70 170 l 70 180 l 80 180 l 80 170 m 80 170 m 310 280 l 310 290 l 320 290 l 320 280 m 320 280 m 50 170 l 50 180 l 60 180 l 60 170 m 60 170 m 320 70 l 320 80 l 330 80 l 330 70 m 330 70 m 60 140 l 60 150 l 70 150 l 70 140 m 70 140 m 330 60 l 330 70 l 340 70 l 340 60 m 340 60 m 100 160 l 100 170 l 110 170 l 110 160 m 110 160 m 210 80 l 210 90 l 220 90 l 220 80 m 220 80 m 240 270 l 240 280 l 250 280 l 250 270 m 250 270 m 220 70 l 220 80 l 230 80 l 230 70 m 230 70 m 150 360 l 150 370 l 160 370 l 160 360 m 160 360 m 270 40 l 270 50 l 280 50 l 280 40 m 280 40 m 120 310 l 120 320 l 130 320 l 130 310 m 130 310 m 360 120 l 360 130 l 370 130 l 370 120 m 370 120 m 140 210 l 140 220 l 150 220 l 150 210 m 150 210 m 290 350 l 290 360 l 300 360 l 300 350 m 300 350 m 300 320 l 300 330 l 310 330 l 310 320 m 310 320 m 50 100 l 50 110 l 60 110 l 60 100 m 60 100 m 320 300 l 320 310 l 330 310 l 330 300 m 330 300 m 300 100 l 300 110 l 310 110 l 310 100 m 310 100 m 90 120 l 90 130 l 100 130 l 100 120 m 100 120 m 70 280 l 70 290 l 80 290 l 80 280 m 80 280 m 340 40 l 340 50 l 350 50 l 350 40 m 350 40 m 230 330 l 230 340 l 240 340 l 240 330 m 240 330 m 300 360 l 300 370 l 310 370 l 310 360 m 310 360 m 90 220 l 90 230 l 100 230 l 100 220 m 100 220 m 240 340 l 240 350 l 250 350 l 250 340 m 250 340 m 230 70 l 230 80 l 240 80 l 240 70 m 240 70 m 260 320 l 260 330 l 270 330 l 270 320 m 270 320 m 130 70 l 130 80 l 140 80 l 140 70 m 140 70 m 140 280 l 140 290 l 150 290 l 150 280 m 150 280 m 40 340 l 40 350 l 50 350 l 50 340 m 50 340 m 180 60 l 180 70 l 190 70 l 190 60 m 190 60 m 160 260 l 160 270 l 170 270 l 170 260 m 170 260 m 320 210 l 320 220 l 330 220 l 330 210 m 330 210 m 60 320 l 60 330 l 70 330 l 70 320 m 70 320 m 300 50 l 300 60 l 310 60 l 310 50 m 310 50 m 330 240 l 330 250 l 340 250 l 340 240 m 340 240 m 80 300 l 80 310 l 90 310 l 90 300 m 90 300 m 330 180 l 330 190 l 340 190 l 340 180 m 340 180 m 100 200 l 100 210 l 110 210 l 110 200 m 110 200 m 80 360 l 80 370 l 90 370 l 90 360 m 90 360 m 210 120 l 210 130 l 220 130 l 220 120 m 220 120 m 270 260 l 270 270 l 280 270 l 280 260 m 280 260 m 120 130 l 120 140 l 130 140 l 130 130 m 130 130 m 360 100 l 360 110 l 370 110 l 370 100 m 370 100 m 260 130 l 260 140 l 270 140 l 270 130 m 270 130 m 130 80 l 130 90 l 140 90 l 140 80 m 140 80 m 270 160 l 270 170 l 280 170 l 280 160 m 280 160 m 150 140 l 150 150 l 160 150 l 160 140 m 160 140 m 40 250 l 40 260 l 50 260 l 50 250 m 50 250 m 280 220 l 280 230 l 290 230 l 290 220 m 290 220 m 180 90 l 180 100 l 190 100 l 190 90 m 190 90 m 160 170 l 160 180 l 170 180 l 170 170 m 170 170 m 50 200 l 50 210 l 60 210 l 60 200 m 60 200 m 290 230 l 290 240 l 300 240 l 300 230 m 300 230 m 300 120 l 300 130 l 310 130 l 310 120 m 310 120 m 70 100 l 70 110 l 80 110 l 80 100 m 80 100 m 50 140 l 50 150 l 60 150 l 60 140 m 60 140 m 320 100 l 320 110 l 330 110 l 330 100 m 330 100 m 350 150 l 350 160 l 360 160 l 360 150 m 360 150 m 200 80 l 200 90 l 210 90 l 210 80 m 210 80 m 340 240 l 340 250 l 350 250 l 350 240 m 350 240 m 210 50 l 210 60 l 220 60 l 220 50 m 220 50 m 350 210 l 350 220 l 360 220 l 360 210 m 360 210 m 220 100 l 220 110 l 230 110 l 230 100 m 230 100 m 200 300 l 200 310 l 210 310 l 210 300 m 210 300 m 250 150 l 250 160 l 260 160 l 260 150 m 260 150 m 140 360 l 140 370 l 150 370 l 150 360 m 150 360 m 210 310 l 210 320 l 220 320 l 220 310 m 220 310 m 130 170 l 130 180 l 140 180 l 140 170 m 140 170 m 220 360 l 220 370 l 230 370 l 230 360 m 230 360 m 270 90 l 270 100 l 280 100 l 280 90 m 280 90 m 140 140 l 140 150 l 150 150 l 150 140 m 150 140 m 150 70 l 150 80 l 160 80 l 160 70 m 160 70 m 280 290 l 280 300 l 290 300 l 290 290 m 290 290 m 180 160 l 180 170 l 190 170 l 190 160 m 190 160 m 160 80 l 160 90 l 170 90 l 170 80 m 170 80 m 140 240 l 140 250 l 150 250 l 150 240 m 150 240 m 170 130 l 170 140 l 180 140 l 180 130 m 180 130 m 150 290 l 150 300 l 160 300 l 160 290 m 160 290 m 300 230 l 300 240 l 310 240 l 310 230 m 310 230 m 40 60 l 40 70 l 50 70 l 50 60 m 50 60 m 70 190 l 70 200 l 80 200 l 80 190 m 80 190 m 60 120 l 60 130 l 70 130 l 70 120 m 70 120 m 330 40 l 330 50 l 340 50 l 340 40 m 340 40 m 290 360 l 290 370 l 300 370 l 300 360 m 300 360 m 100 60 l 100 70 l 110 70 l 110 60 m 110 60 m 340 350 l 340 360 l 350 360 l 350 350 m 350 350 m 80 260 l 80 270 l 90 270 l 90 260 m 90 260 m 230 260 l 230 270 l 240 270 l 240 260 m 240 260 m 110 150 l 110 160 l 120 160 l 120 150 m 120 150 m 240 210 l 240 220 l 250 220 l 250 210 m 250 210 m 200 210 l 200 220 l 210 220 l 210 210 m 210 210 m 210 320 l 210 330 l 220 330 l 220 320 m 220 320 m 360 240 l 360 250 l 370 250 l 370 240 m 370 240 m 220 310 l 220 320 l 230 320 l 230 310 m 230 310 m 270 60 l 270 70 l 280 70 l 280 60 m 280 60 m 120 330 l 120 340 l 130 340 l 130 330 m 130 330 m 180 270 l 180 280 l 190 280 l 190 270 m 190 270 m 190 260 l 190 270 l 200 270 l 200 260 m 200 260 m 170 60 l 170 70 l 180 70 l 180 60 m 180 60 m 300 300 l 300 310 l 310 310 l 310 300 m 310 300 m 280 100 l 280 110 l 290 110 l 290 100 m 290 100 m 160 290 l 160 300 l 170 300 l 170 290 m 170 290 m 310 230 l 310 240 l 320 240 l 320 230 m 320 230 m 170 320 l 170 330 l 180 330 l 180 320 m 180 320 m 320 240 l 320 250 l 330 250 l 330 240 m 330 240 m 60 70 l 60 80 l 70 80 l 70 70 m 70 70 m 300 80 l 300 90 l 310 90 l 310 80 m 310 80 m 330 290 l 330 300 l 340 300 l 340 290 m 340 290 m 70 300 l 70 310 l 80 310 l 80 300 m 80 300 m 100 90 l 100 100 l 110 100 l 110 90 m 110 90 m 340 100 l 340 110 l 350 110 l 350 100 m 350 100 m 80 330 l 80 340 l 90 340 l 90 330 m 90 330 m 70 360 l 70 370 l 80 370 l 80 360 m 80 360 m 100 350 l 100 360 l 110 360 l 110 350 m 110 350 m 250 330 l 250 340 l 260 340 l 260 330 m 260 330 m 240 100 l 240 110 l 250 110 l 250 100 m 250 100 m 220 220 l 220 230 l 230 230 l 230 220 m 230 220 m 270 310 l 270 320 l 280 320 l 280 310 m 280 310 m 360 50 l 360 60 l 370 60 l 370 50 m 370 50 m 180 340 l 180 350 l 190 350 l 190 340 m 190 340 m 140 100 l 140 110 l 150 110 l 150 100 m 150 100 m 280 170 l 280 180 l 290 180 l 290 170 m 290 170 m 160 200 l 160 210 l 170 210 l 170 200 m 170 200 m 190 90 l 190 100 l 200 100 l 200 90 m 200 90 m 170 250 l 170 260 l 180 260 l 180 250 m 180 250 m 320 230 l 320 240 l 330 240 l 330 230 m 330 230 m 60 300 l 60 310 l 70 310 l 70 300 m 70 300 m 300 190 l 300 200 l 310 200 l 310 190 m 310 190 m 70 70 l 70 80 l 80 80 l 80 70 m 80 70 m 340 130 l 340 140 l 350 140 l 350 130 m 350 130 m 80 80 l 80 90 l 90 90 l 90 80 m 90 80 m 330 160 l 330 170 l 340 170 l 340 160 m 340 160 m 100 260 l 100 270 l 110 270 l 110 260 m 110 260 m 210 180 l 210 190 l 220 190 l 220 180 m 220 180 m 110 270 l 110 280 l 120 280 l 120 270 m 120 270 m 260 250 l 260 260 l 270 260 l 270 250 m 270 250 m 240 170 l 240 180 l 250 180 l 250 170 m 250 170 m 130 360 l 130 370 l 140 370 l 140 360 m 140 360 m 250 40 l 250 50 l 260 50 l 260 40 m 260 40 m 210 360 l 210 370 l 220 370 l 220 360 m 220 360 m 360 280 l 360 290 l 370 290 l 370 280 m 370 280 m 260 190 l 260 200 l 270 200 l 270 190 m 270 190 m 130 140 l 130 150 l 140 150 l 140 140 m 140 140 m 270 180 l 270 190 l 280 190 l 280 180 m 280 180 m 140 50 l 140 60 l 150 60 l 150 50 m 150 50 m 280 240 l 280 250 l 290 250 l 290 240 m 290 240 m 160 190 l 160 200 l 170 200 l 170 190 m 170 190 m 290 210 l 290 220 l 300 220 l 300 210 m 300 210 m 60 250 l 60 260 l 70 260 l 70 250 m 70 250 m 300 260 l 300 270 l 310 270 l 310 260 m 310 260 m 40 170 l 40 180 l 50 180 l 50 170 m 50 170 m 70 120 l 70 130 l 80 130 l 80 120 m 80 120 m 80 70 l 80 80 l 90 80 l 90 70 m 90 70 m 320 40 l 320 50 l 330 50 l 330 40 m 330 40 m 200 100 l 200 110 l 210 110 l 210 100 m 210 100 m 230 230 l 230 240 l 240 240 l 240 230 m 240 230 m 210 110 l 210 120 l 220 120 l 220 110 m 220 110 m 350 230 l 350 240 l 360 240 l 360 230 m 360 230 m 220 80 l 220 90 l 230 90 l 230 80 m 230 80 m 200 320 l 200 330 l 210 330 l 210 320 m 210 320 m 360 350 l 360 360 l 370 360 l 370 350 m 370 350 m 260 100 l 260 110 l 270 110 l 270 100 m 270 100 m 220 340 l 220 350 l 230 350 l 230 340 m 230 340 m 270 110 l 270 120 l 280 120 l 280 110 m 280 110 m 140 120 l 140 130 l 150 130 l 150 120 m 150 120 m 150 90 l 150 100 l 160 100 l 160 90 m 160 90 m 280 310 l 280 320 l 290 320 l 290 310 m 290 310 m 160 100 l 160 110 l 170 110 l 170 100 m 170 100 m 140 220 l 140 230 l 150 230 l 150 220 m 150 220 m 300 210 l 300 220 l 310 220 l 310 210 m 310 210 m 40 80 l 40 90 l 50 90 l 50 80 m 50 80 m 160 320 l 160 330 l 170 330 l 170 320 m 170 320 m 310 320 l 310 330 l 320 330 l 320 320 m 320 320 m 320 350 l 320 360 l 330 360 l 330 350 m 330 350 m 60 100 l 60 110 l 70 110 l 70 100 m 70 100 m 100 40 l 100 50 l 110 50 l 110 40 m 110 40 m 80 200 l 80 210 l 90 210 l 90 200 m 90 200 m 230 280 l 230 290 l 240 290 l 240 280 m 240 280 m 60 360 l 60 370 l 70 370 l 70 360 m 70 360 m 100 300 l 100 310 l 110 310 l 110 300 m 110 300 m 250 220 l 250 230 l 260 230 l 260 220 m 260 220 m 360 260 l 360 270 l 370 270 l 370 260 m 370 260 m 220 290 l 220 300 l 230 300 l 230 290 m 230 290 m 270 320 l 270 330 l 280 330 l 280 320 m 280 320 m 180 250 l 180 260 l 190 260 l 190 250 m 190 250 m 140 330 l 140 340 l 150 340 l 150 330 m 150 330 m 150 200 l 150 210 l 160 210 l 160 200 m 160 200 m 300 280 l 300 290 l 310 290 l 310 280 m 310 280 m 40 310 l 40 320 l 50 320 l 50 310 m 50 310 m 160 310 l 160 320 l 170 320 l 170 310 m 170 310 m 310 250 l 310 260 l 320 260 l 320 250 m 320 250 m 50 300 l 50 310 l 60 310 l 60 300 m 60 300 m 170 300 l 170 310 l 180 310 l 180 300 m 180 300 m 300 60 l 300 70 l 310 70 l 310 60 m 310 60 m 330 270 l 330 280 l 340 280 l 340 270 m 340 270 m 70 320 l 70 330 l 80 330 l 80 320 m 80 320 m 310 150 l 310 160 l 320 160 l 320 150 m 320 150 m 340 80 l 340 90 l 350 90 l 350 80 m 350 80 m 240 300 l 240 310 l 250 310 l 250 300 m 250 300 m 200 140 l 200 150 l 210 150 l 210 140 m 210 140 m 100 330 l 100 340 l 110 340 l 110 330 m 110 330 m 230 110 l 230 120 l 240 120 l 240 110 m 240 110 m 210 150 l 210 160 l 220 160 l 220 150 m 220 150 m 120 360 l 120 370 l 130 370 l 130 360 m 130 360 m 260 200 l 260 210 l 270 210 l 270 200 m 270 200 m 240 40 l 240 50 l 250 50 l 250 40 m 250 40 m 220 200 l 220 210 l 230 210 l 230 200 m 230 200 m 250 90 l 250 100 l 260 100 l 260 90 m 260 90 m 120 100 l 120 110 l 130 110 l 130 100 m 130 100 m 360 70 l 360 80 l 370 80 l 370 70 m 370 70 m 260 140 l 260 150 l 270 150 l 270 140 m 270 140 m 140 80 l 140 90 l 150 90 l 150 80 m 150 80 m 190 290 l 190 300 l 200 300 l 200 290 m 200 290 m 40 220 l 40 230 l 50 230 l 50 220 m 50 220 m 280 190 l 280 200 l 290 200 l 290 190 m 290 190 m 180 100 l 180 110 l 190 110 l 190 100 m 190 100 m 190 110 l 190 120 l 200 120 l 200 110 m 200 110 m 170 230 l 170 240 l 180 240 l 180 230 m 180 230 m 60 280 l 60 290 l 70 290 l 70 280 m 70 280 m 300 170 l 300 180 l 310 180 l 310 170 m 310 170 m 40 120 l 40 130 l 50 130 l 50 120 m 50 120 m 310 40 l 310 50 l 320 50 l 320 40 m 320 40 m 340 190 l 340 200 l 350 200 l 350 190 m 350 190 m 80 100 l 80 110 l 90 110 l 90 100 m 90 100 m 330 140 l 330 150 l 340 150 l 340 140 m 340 140 m 100 240 l 100 250 l 110 250 l 110 240 m 110 240 m 230 160 l 230 170 l 240 170 l 240 160 m 240 160 m 110 210 l 110 220 l 120 220 l 120 210 m 120 210 m 360 300 l 360 310 l 370 310 l 370 300 m 370 300 m 130 220 l 130 230 l 140 230 l 140 220 m 140 220 m 50 240 l 50 250 l 60 250 l 60 240 m 60 240 m 190 160 l 190 170 l 200 170 l 200 160 m 200 160 m 60 230 l 60 240 l 70 240 l 70 230 m 70 230 m 300 240 l 300 250 l 310 250 l 310 240 m 310 240 m 50 180 l 50 190 l 60 190 l 60 180 m 60 180 m 80 170 l 80 180 l 90 180 l 90 170 m 90 170 m 320 60 l 320 70 l 330 70 l 330 60 m 330 60 m 60 170 l 60 180 l 70 180 l 70 170 m 70 170 m 90 40 l 90 50 l 100 50 l 100 40 m 100 40 m 330 70 l 330 80 l 340 80 l 340 70 m 340 70 m 50 360 l 50 370 l 60 370 l 60 360 m 60 360 m 340 280 l 340 290 l 350 290 l 350 280 m 350 280 m 210 90 l 210 100 l 220 100 l 220 90 m 220 90 m 110 180 l 110 190 l 120 190 l 120 180 m 120 180 m 240 260 l 240 270 l 250 270 l 250 260 m 250 260 m 220 60 l 220 70 l 230 70 l 230 60 m 230 60 m 200 340 l 200 350 l 210 350 l 210 340 m 210 340 m 210 350 l 210 360 l 220 360 l 220 350 m 220 350 m 220 320 l 220 330 l 230 330 l 230 320 m 230 320 m 270 50 l 270 60 l 280 60 l 280 50 m 280 50 m 120 300 l 120 310 l 130 310 l 130 300 m 130 300 m 180 200 l 180 210 l 190 210 l 190 200 m 190 200 m 290 280 l 290 290 l 300 290 l 300 280 m 300 280 m 190 250 l 190 260 l 200 260 l 200 250 m 200 250 m 170 90 l 170 100 l 180 100 l 180 90 m 180 90 m 40 100 l 40 110 l 50 110 l 50 100 m 50 100 m 280 70 l 280 80 l 290 80 l 290 70 m 290 70 m 310 340 l 310 350 l 320 350 l 320 340 m 320 340 m 320 290 l 320 300 l 330 300 l 330 290 m 330 290 m 60 80 l 60 90 l 70 90 l 70 80 m 70 80 m 100 100 l 100 110 l 110 110 l 110 100 m 110 100 m 340 70 l 340 80 l 350 80 l 350 70 m 350 70 m 80 220 l 80 230 l 90 230 l 90 220 m 90 220 m 230 300 l 230 310 l 240 310 l 240 300 m 240 300 m 200 250 l 200 260 l 210 260 l 210 250 m 210 250 m 100 280 l 100 290 l 110 290 l 110 280 m 110 280 m 250 200 l 250 210 l 260 210 l 260 200 m 260 200 m 270 360 l 270 370 l 280 370 l 280 360 m 280 360 m 230 40 l 230 50 l 240 50 l 240 40 m 240 40 m 210 200 l 210 210 l 220 210 l 220 200 m 220 200 m 220 270 l 220 280 l 230 280 l 230 270 m 230 270 m 120 50 l 120 60 l 130 60 l 130 50 m 130 50 m 190 220 l 190 230 l 200 230 l 200 220 m 200 220 m 40 330 l 40 340 l 50 340 l 50 330 m 50 330 m 280 140 l 280 150 l 290 150 l 290 140 m 290 140 m 310 270 l 310 280 l 320 280 l 320 270 m 320 270 m 320 200 l 320 210 l 330 210 l 330 200 m 330 200 m 300 40 l 300 50 l 310 50 l 310 40 m 310 40 m 70 340 l 70 350 l 80 350 l 80 340 m 80 340 m 330 190 l 330 200 l 340 200 l 340 190 m 340 190 m 200 160 l 200 170 l 210 170 l 210 160 m 210 160 m 250 290 l 250 300 l 260 300 l 260 290 m 260 290 m 230 130 l 230 140 l 240 140 l 240 130 m 240 130 m 210 130 l 210 140 l 220 140 l 220 130 m 220 130 m 240 60 l 240 70 l 250 70 l 250 60 m 250 60 m 220 180 l 220 190 l 230 190 l 230 180 m 230 180 m 270 270 l 270 280 l 280 280 l 280 270 m 280 270 m 250 70 l 250 80 l 260 80 l 260 70 m 260 70 m 360 90 l 360 100 l 370 100 l 370 90 m 370 90 m 130 90 l 130 100 l 140 100 l 140 90 m 140 90 m 270 170 l 270 180 l 280 180 l 280 170 m 280 170 m 140 60 l 140 70 l 150 70 l 150 60 m 150 60 m 190 310 l 190 320 l 200 320 l 200 310 m 200 310 m 150 150 l 150 160 l 160 160 l 160 150 m 160 150 m 40 240 l 40 250 l 50 250 l 50 240 m 50 240 m 280 210 l 280 220 l 290 220 l 290 210 m 290 210 m 50 210 l 50 220 l 60 220 l 60 210 m 60 210 m 290 160 l 290 170 l 300 170 l 300 160 m 300 160 m 190 50 l 190 60 l 200 60 l 200 50 m 200 50 m 60 260 l 60 270 l 70 270 l 70 260 m 70 260 m 300 150 l 300 160 l 310 160 l 310 150 m 310 150 m 50 150 l 50 160 l 60 160 l 60 150 m 60 150 m 340 170 l 340 180 l 350 180 l 350 170 m 350 170 m 80 40 l 80 50 l 90 50 l 90 40 m 90 40 m 40 360 l 40 370 l 50 370 l 50 360 m 50 360 m 350 120 l 350 130 l 360 130 l 360 120 m 360 120 m 330 120 l 330 130 l 340 130 l 340 120 m 340 120 m 100 140 l 100 150 l 110 150 l 110 140 m 110 140 m 340 270 l 340 280 l 350 280 l 350 270 m 350 270 m 230 180 l 230 190 l 240 190 l 240 180 m 240 180 m 110 230 l 110 240 l 120 240 l 120 230 m 120 230 m 350 260 l 350 270 l 360 270 l 360 260 m 360 260 m 220 130 l 220 140 l 230 140 l 230 130 m 230 130 m 250 160 l 250 170 l 260 170 l 260 160 m 260 160 m 120 190 l 120 200 l 130 200 l 130 190 m 130 190 m 270 140 l 270 150 l 280 150 l 280 140 m 280 140 m 140 170 l 140 180 l 150 180 l 150 170 m 150 170 m 130 200 l 130 210 l 140 210 l 140 200 m 140 200 m 280 280 l 280 290 l 290 290 l 290 280 m 290 280 m 170 140 l 170 150 l 180 150 l 180 140 m 180 140 m 60 210 l 60 220 l 70 220 l 70 210 m 70 210 m 40 50 l 40 60 l 50 60 l 50 50 m 50 50 m 50 160 l 50 170 l 60 170 l 60 160 m 60 160 m 80 190 l 80 200 l 90 200 l 90 190 m 90 190 m 320 320 l 320 330 l 330 330 l 330 320 m 330 320 m 60 150 l 60 160 l 70 160 l 70 150 m 70 150 m 90 180 l 90 190 l 100 190 l 100 180 m 100 180 m 80 250 l 80 260 l 90 260 l 90 250 m 90 250 m 110 120 l 110 130 l 120 130 l 120 120 m 120 120 m 240 200 l 240 210 l 250 210 l 250 200 m 250 200 m 200 200 l 200 210 l 210 210 l 210 200 m 210 200 m 250 250 l 250 260 l 260 260 l 260 250 m 260 250 m 360 230 l 360 240 l 370 240 l 370 230 m 370 230 m 220 300 l 220 310 l 230 310 l 230 300 m 230 300 m 270 70 l 270 80 l 280 80 l 280 70 m 280 70 m 180 260 l 180 270 l 190 270 l 190 260 m 190 260 m 190 270 l 190 280 l 200 280 l 200 270 m 200 270 m 150 350 l 150 360 l 160 360 l 160 350 m 160 350 m 40 280 l 40 290 l 50 290 l 50 280 m 50 280 m 320 310 l 320 320 l 330 320 l 330 310 m 330 310 m 60 60 l 60 70 l 70 70 l 70 60 m 70 60 m 100 80 l 100 90 l 110 90 l 110 80 m 110 80 m 80 320 l 80 330 l 90 330 l 90 320 m 90 320 m 90 210 l 90 220 l 100 220 l 100 210 m 100 210 m 240 350 l 240 360 l 250 360 l 250 350 m 250 350 m 100 340 l 100 350 l 110 350 l 110 340 m 110 340 m 210 260 l 210 270 l 220 270 l 220 260 m 220 260 m 260 330 l 260 340 l 270 340 l 270 330 m 270 330 m 270 280 l 270 290 l 280 290 l 280 280 m 280 280 m 120 70 l 120 80 l 130 80 l 130 70 m 130 70 m 360 40 l 360 50 l 370 50 l 370 40 m 370 40 m 130 60 l 130 70 l 140 70 l 140 60 m 140 60 m 140 290 l 140 300 l 150 300 l 150 290 m 150 290 m 190 320 l 190 330 l 200 330 l 200 320 m 200 320 m 150 240 l 150 250 l 160 250 l 160 240 m 160 240 m 40 350 l 40 360 l 50 360 l 50 350 m 50 350 m 290 130 l 290 140 l 300 140 l 300 130 m 300 130 m 170 260 l 170 270 l 180 270 l 180 260 m 180 260 m 320 220 l 320 230 l 330 230 l 330 220 m 330 220 m 60 330 l 60 340 l 70 340 l 70 330 m 70 330 m 70 40 l 70 50 l 80 50 l 80 40 m 80 40 m 350 170 l 350 180 l 360 180 l 360 170 m 360 170 m 90 300 l 90 310 l 100 310 l 100 300 m 100 300 m 330 170 l 330 180 l 340 180 l 340 170 m 340 170 m 340 220 l 340 230 l 350 230 l 350 220 m 350 220 m 230 150 l 230 160 l 240 160 l 240 150 m 240 150 m 110 240 l 110 250 l 120 250 l 120 240 m 120 240 m 260 240 l 260 250 l 270 250 l 270 240 m 270 240 m 240 160 l 240 170 l 250 170 l 250 160 m 250 160 m 270 210 l 270 220 l 280 220 l 280 210 m 280 210 m 260 180 l 260 190 l 270 190 l 270 180 m 270 180 m 270 190 l 270 200 l 280 200 l 280 190 m 280 190 m 140 40 l 140 50 l 150 50 l 150 40 m 150 40 m 120 200 l 120 210 l 130 210 l 130 200 m 130 200 m 150 170 l 150 180 l 160 180 l 160 170 m 160 170 m 160 180 l 160 190 l 170 190 l 170 180 m 170 180 m 50 270 l 50 280 l 60 280 l 60 270 m 60 270 m 60 240 l 60 250 l 70 250 l 70 240 m 70 240 m 300 130 l 300 140 l 310 140 l 310 130 m 310 130 m 40 160 l 40 170 l 50 170 l 50 160 m 50 160 m 70 130 l 70 140 l 80 140 l 80 130 m 80 130 m 80 60 l 80 70 l 90 70 l 90 60 m 90 60 m 60 180 l 60 190 l 70 190 l 70 180 m 70 180 m 350 140 l 350 150 l 360 150 l 360 140 m 360 140 m 330 100 l 330 110 l 340 110 l 340 100 m 340 100 m 200 90 l 200 100 l 210 100 l 210 90 m 210 90 m 100 120 l 100 130 l 110 130 l 110 120 m 110 120 m 340 250 l 340 260 l 350 260 l 350 250 m 350 250 m 250 360 l 250 370 l 260 370 l 260 360 m 260 360 m 240 150 l 240 160 l 250 160 l 250 150 m 250 150 m 330 360 l 330 370 l 340 370 l 340 360 m 340 360 m 250 140 l 250 150 l 260 150 l 260 140 m 260 140 m 210 300 l 210 310 l 220 310 l 220 300 m 220 300 m 130 160 l 130 170 l 140 170 l 140 160 m 140 160 m 270 80 l 270 90 l 280 90 l 280 80 m 280 80 m 130 260 l 130 270 l 140 270 l 140 260 m 140 260 m 280 300 l 280 310 l 290 310 l 290 300 m 290 300 m 180 170 l 180 180 l 190 180 l 190 170 m 190 170 m 160 90 l 160 100 l 170 100 l 170 90 m 170 90 m 140 250 l 140 260 l 150 260 l 150 250 m 150 250 m 190 120 l 190 130 l 200 130 l 200 120 m 200 120 m 170 120 l 170 130 l 180 130 l 180 120 m 180 120 m 150 280 l 150 290 l 160 290 l 160 280 m 160 280 m 300 200 l 300 210 l 310 210 l 310 200 m 310 200 m 40 70 l 40 80 l 50 80 l 50 70 m 50 70 m 280 40 l 280 50 l 290 50 l 290 40 m 290 40 m 70 180 l 70 190 l 80 190 l 80 180 m 80 180 m 90 160 l 90 170 l 100 170 l 100 160 m 100 160 m 330 350 l 330 360 l 340 360 l 340 350 m 340 350 m 100 70 l 100 80 l 110 80 l 110 70 m 110 70 m 340 320 l 340 330 l 350 330 l 350 320 m 350 320 m 230 290 l 230 300 l 240 300 l 240 290 m 240 290 m 240 220 l 240 230 l 250 230 l 250 220 m 250 220 m 210 230 l 210 240 l 220 240 l 220 230 m 220 230 m 360 250 l 360 260 l 370 260 l 370 250 m 370 250 m 220 280 l 220 290 l 230 290 l 230 280 m 230 280 m 270 330 l 270 340 l 280 340 l 280 330 m 280 330 m 120 340 l 120 350 l 130 350 l 130 340 m 130 340 m 360 150 l 360 160 l 370 160 l 370 150 m 370 150 m 290 320 l 290 330 l 300 330 l 300 320 m 300 320 m 190 210 l 190 220 l 200 220 l 200 210 m 200 210 m 40 300 l 40 310 l 50 310 l 50 300 m 50 300 m 320 250 l 320 260 l 330 260 l 330 250 m 330 250 m 60 40 l 60 50 l 70 50 l 70 40 m 70 40 m 300 90 l 300 100 l 310 100 l 310 90 m 310 90 m 330 280 l 330 290 l 340 290 l 340 280 m 340 280 m 70 330 l 70 340 l 80 340 l 80 330 m 80 330 m 80 340 l 80 350 l 90 350 l 90 340 m 90 340
莎拉  如果我真的死了
Sara, if I... if I do die,
别在墓碑上刻卡尼尔·乌提斯
don't let them put Kaniel Outis on the headstone
因为那从来不是真正的我
because that's never who I was.
让他们刻上我的真名
Make them put my real name,
那个始终如一的我
the man I have always been.
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
Michael Scofield.